KADE HIGGINS

DATA SCIENTIST

CONTACT

KHIGGINS115@GMAIL.COM

PROFILE

Empathetic and Curious Queer Texan & Data Scientist with a professional and educational background in GIS and spatial data analysis. My experience blends demographically focused location intelligence with data science to create meaningful, actionable insights. My work is driven by asking purposeful, relevant questions and conducting thoughtful exploratory analysis to understand problems more fully. A passionate, life-long learner, I am always searching for new ways to use data to generate positive change in the world.

SKILLS

Languages/Libraries

 Python, Pandas, Numpy, sci-kit Learn, geo-plotlib, HTML/CSS, JS, SQL

Data Science

 Machine Learning (Classification/Regression), Natural Language Processing, Web scraping, Data cleaning, Data Visualization

MISC

 Streamlit, ArcGIS Desktop/Pro, Turf.js, Leaflet.js, spatial data analysis, web mapping, Adobe Illustrator

EXPERIENCE

DATA SCIENCE FELLOW

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | SEP 2021 - DEC 2021

Applied Data Science tools/techniques to build predictive models for Housing Prices. Built NLP model to classify Reddit.com text. Capstone project used regression and k-means clustering to explore relationship between alcohol abuse prevalence & self-harm mortality at county level.

JR. GIS ANALYST

MOSAIC NORTH AMERICA | APR 2018 - MAY 2020

Utilized sales/demographic/psychographic data to provide program & consumer insights. Provided actionable business analysis in spatial context. Created optimized national territory coverage & cost efficient routing for client retail field teams. Developed internal interactive mapping tools, Spearheaded "Mappy Hour" training for analytics team.

GIS INTERN

AMERICAN RED CROSS | JUN 2016 - AUG 2016

Assisted in analysis of geospatial data. Created interactive web apps to visualize spatial/categorical data. Digitized satellite imagery to contribute to Humanitarian OpenStreetMap team (HOT OSM) tasks as needed.

EDUCATION

DATA SCIENCE IMMERSIVE STUDENT

GENERAL ASSEMBLY | DEC 2021 480+ hour immersive data science program

B.S. GEOGRAPHIC INFO. SCIENCE & TECHNOLOGY

TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY | DEC 2017

Geospatial Technology degree with focus on Computation, Design & Analysis. GIS & computer science coursework.

LEADERSHIP & AWARDS

PRESIDENT (2014 - 2015)/ VP (2013 - 2014) LGBTQ AGGIES Led 100+ member LGBTQ+ student org - organized social events, speakers, and educational programs to improve campus climate for queer students.

BUCK WEIRUS SPIRIT AWARD (2015)

This award honors students who demonstrate high involvement, create positive experiences, impact student life at Texas A&M and enhance the Aggie Spirit